

CONTACT INFO

E-mail s.saadat@sharif.edu

Phone Nr +98 900 12 60060

Github github.com/SaeeSaadat

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/SaeeSaadat

ABOUT ME

I'm a self-proclaimed tech fanatic.

I've spent my life learning about tech and I've devoted the last four years to honing my skills as a software engineer, working in prestigious software companies, and participating in research projects in NLP and IoT. This journey has led me to found AYOT, my IoT platform startup.

With my skills, experience, thirst for knowledge, and positive attitude, I'm confident I can make a meaningful impact on any project or team I join. I'm seeking brilliant mentors to help me grow and guide me on my journey.

SKILLS

• • •	Python, Swift, Git, PostgreSQL, Bash Automation
• • •	Problem solving, Brain storming and generating ideas
\bullet \bullet \circ	Leadership, Fast learning, Good communication
\bullet \bullet \circ	Software system design, Golang, Arduino
	Attention to details, pizzazz and having a flair for the the

Languages

- Persian (native)
- English (Fluent)

EDUCATION

Computer engineering, Bachelor of science

2018-2023

Sharif University of technology | Tehran, Iran

• GPA: 3.58

NODET, Helli High school

2016-2019

National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents | Tehran, Iran

• GPA: 4.0

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

2023-Present

Natural language processing Lab | Sharif University of Technology (with Dr. Ehsanedin Asgari)

- Working on the Persian language.
- Working on Fanoos, a messenger with NLP bots capable of understanding the text and assisting the user.
- Researching POS taggers and normalizers using label-studio, Hazm and Dadma.

TEACHER ASSISTANT

2019-Present

Various courses | Sharif university of technology

- Database design (Head TA) Dr. Varmazyar
- Database design Dr. Baharifard
- Computer simulations Dr. Safaei
- Computer networks Dr. Arshadi

ENTREPRENEURSHIP IN TECH

2020-2022

Beginning of AYOT | Sharif Innovation park

- Learning entrepreneurship and starting a business in tech.
- Researching and exploring IoT, Smart homes, PaaS and the startup ecosystem.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FOUNDER AND SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2021-Present

AYOT - IoT Platform For Smart Homes | Sharif innovation park, Tehran

- Following my passion for both entrepreneurship and IoT.
- With the help of two of our brilliant professors and four of my peers.
- Building an MVP from the ground up; Micro service server, MQTT broker, iOS application and a smart fan controlled by an Arduino with an ESP8266 chip.
- meeting with esteemed home appliances manufacturers and coming up with new ideas in every related field.
- Dealing with managing resources, Investments, security challenges and more.
- Working with: Python(FastAPI), EMQX(MQTT), PostgreSQL, Swift(iQS), PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, REST-API, Keycloak, SQLAlchemy, SSL and Cloud deployment.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2022-2023

Digikala::Jet | Tehran, Iran

- Working on the number one E-commerce and Q-commerce website in the country.
- Working on (and refactoring) a critical legacy code while starting the redesign process.
- In the legacy code, I worked on a monolithic system with PHP, MySQL, Docker, Redis, Elasticsearch, Memcached, Kafka, Gitlab, and Jenkins.
- System redesign process for a multi-million dollar business with a large client base and turning a monolithic architecture with over 200,000 lines of code into a clean, readable micro-service one; Also worked with Golang, PostgreSQL, Redis, Tyk, k8s, RabbitMQ and Elasticsearch.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ostadkar.ir | Tehran, Iran

- Second semester of computer engineering department's Co-Op initiative.
- Working with brilliant mentors on my first software engineering job as a back-end developer.
- Working with python, Flask, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Redis, SQLAlchemy, Keycloak, gitlab CI/CD, FTP, SSH tunnels, Bash, Docker swarm, Nginx.

IOS DEVELOPER 2020-2021

Farazpardazan - Hamrah Novin Mobile Banking | Tehran, Iran

- First semester of computer engineering department's Co-Op initiative.
- Entering with absolutely zero experience or knowledge about Swift, iOS or anything about software development.
- A three month self-learning phase (with some help from my mentors) and then immediately joining the production team and handling tasks like a pro. Learning Swift, REST-API, RXSwift, TCP/IP, OAuth, Fastlane, CoreData, Alamofire and mobile banking.
- Learning about software engineering, Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Soft Skills and Professional Etiquettes.

FIELDS OF INTEREST

I am passionate about technology and its potential to make a positive impact on the world. I am confident in my ability to quickly learn and adapt to any field within tech, in order to contribute to its development, research, or implementation. While I am interested in all areas of technology, my current favorite topics include:

• • •	IoT and Smart Homes
• • •	Software Engineering
\bullet \bullet \circ	Human-Computer Interaction
\bullet \bullet \circ	Natural Language Processing
\bullet \bullet \circ	Cyber Security
\bullet \circ \circ	Augmented Reality